Is that shell?
And there's Miss Bridget.
But the other day
when I saw you,
my heart was racing so fast
I couldn't bear it.
So what did you
want my advice about?
I don't think I said
anything about needing advice.
I just wanted to take a walk.
So don't try to fool me. It's
Chale, right?
Give me the details.
Are you two getting closer now?
Huh?
Or not? It's been a whole week.
He spent every night
working as a
model for Keith's
new sugar confection.
And what are you doing?
Look at you.
Out on a stroll. Meanwhile, Master
Jonas has been working hard.
So what?
Are you finished already?
Oh, I know you've given up on.
Be quiet. That's enough.
I've decided to put
my all
into this year's confection.
It'll be something
I want to create.
And yet I can tell by your face
you don't even see
me as a threat.
Look, Jonas. I'm sure of it now.
I really hate you.
Something he wants to create.
Uh, looks like they're
done for today. Yes.
May I ask why you requested
to use shall as your model?
That's simple. The Royal
Family tends to respond
well to sugar confections
that feature a fairy motif.
In the Church of Saint Louis
and Bell our lands had temple.
There's a book on their
history with sugar confections.
Ma. Why does the royal family
prefer pieces resembling fairies?
Go to Saint Louis
and Bell tomorrow.
Though it's one of our
few precious days off.
There's something I need
to look into.
If I'm fortunate,
there might be knowledge
I can use to create my piece
for the exhibition,
so I hope you'll come
there with me. As you wish.
Sorry, Shel. I shouldn't
have made you come along.
What's the matter, Scarecrow?
It's not like you to be so meek.
I'm not. I was just thinking you
might have other plans
already or something.
I don't know,
like a date with Miss Brigitte.
Miss Brigitte, do I know her?
Don't deny it.
I saw the whole
thing yesterday afternoon.
Right behind the dorms.
You two were hugging.
So her name is Brigitte. That's the
first I've heard him. Really?
So you don't even ask
a woman's name before you?
She kept chattering about
how she wanted to buy me,
and I found it annoying,
so I told
her she'd have to steal my wing.
Trust me, there have always
been humans like that.
Oh, that's all it was. I noticed
you've been a little out
of sorts since yesterday, I see.
If it is anything, it's you.
Huh?
I'm sorry,
but the library is closed.
It is currently being renovated.
So your book, what was it again?
It's on confections
in the royal family.
Um,
I believe we may have something.
The older books
are all in ancient
Indian scripts,
so you can't read them.
But I'll let you take a look.
Oh,
is that an Indian two up there?
That's the battle between King
Cedric and the Fairy King, huh?
Now that I think of it, I've
never known
the Fairy King's name.
Resolve a several sash.
Wait, how do you know that?
I've known it my entire life.
I guess
the obsidian that I was born
from must have known it too.
I can translate
that if you like.
You're kidding. You read
old Islandian. I suppose I do.
The founding king. Cedric was
the fairy King's slave. Really?
But then the Fairy King, seeing
Cedric's courage and sincerity,
became friends with him
and set him free.
King Cedric was moved.
He respected the Fairy
King for his great integrity and
strength. They became quite close.
They were friends. The fairy
King and our king Cedric.
The two men searched
tirelessly for a way
that both factions could
live in harmony.
But while the humans and fairies
each revered their respective leaders,
the races continued
to hate each other.
A war broke out
and their fates grew dark.
In the end, the Fairy King was
defeated, though Cedric was victorious.
He grieved deeply for
his lost friend.
To honor him, he had a sugar
confection made in his
image and offered
up a prayer to the heavens.
Cedric wished
that the world they had dreamed
of could one day become reality,
and then a power
which could bring
incredibly good fortune came
to dwell within that confection.
That's the whole story.
The way I heard it, God wanted
humankind to be
rulers over everything.
And then the first
human woman fell
in love with the fairy king.
She swore loyalty to him.
King Cedric
was the one who saved us.
He cleansed the world of her sin
and rebuilt everything
the way God originally wanted.
It's so different from
what you just told me.
But it's what
our religion teaches us.
If the truth doesn't suit the people
in power, it gets rewritten.
That's wrong.
Why though? Why would King
Cedric create a world
like this one
where humans force
fairies to become their
servants?
Why couldn't we be equals?
Because he wasn't the one
who created it this way.
Cedric did win the war,
after all.
He probably continued
to search for a way to coexist.
But for whatever reason, he failed.
And this is what happened.
The details don't
make a difference.
We are not alike at all.
Do you mean humans and fairies?
Please don't say that. Why?
No. There's no difference.
Not in my eyes.
Shall I have all these feelings?
The royal family prefers
sugar confections with
fairies because they
want to atone for
failing to carry
out Cedric's will.
Or that's what I think, anyway.
Shall.
Are.
I see it now.
That's what I was looking for.
I found it.
The thing I want to create most.
So how was your little
excursion? It was perfect.
I picked out the motif
for my piece,
which means it's time to get
to work, Mr. Leopard.
Will you lend me a hand?
Um, sure. Leave it to me.
Shall.
If you wouldn't mind, I'd
like you to stay while I work.
I won't hinder you.
Stay with me.
The wish
that our founding king and
the fairy King shared within
their hearts. I'll give it form.
I see she's finally
starting on her piece.
Thank goodness she was making
me worry.
Why is that? It seemed like
something was troubling her.
I almost told her
the truth that her
entire future is riding
on this year.
I had to stop myself,
see, if I had said
that,
I wouldn't be fighting fair.
She was troubled. Why stop.
Saying that?
All I ever hear from anyone is
you can't. And it's impossible.
Some things just can't be done,
you know?
And girl's been acknowledged
as a real.
How am I supposed to sleep
if they keep making
such a racket? Shall. It's you,
that woman crazy.
Not to mention she's.
Wildly obsessed with you.
She keeps begging
Elliot to buy you after she
learned you weren't for sale.
She wanted him to get someone
to steal your wing. Be careful.
Good thing I'm not a fool.
Oh, well, I warned you.
Careful. Good. Now break time.
Huh?
Thirsty?
Are you all right? You look
like you're about to pass out.
Thank you. Keith. And you're
right, I am exhausted.
Probably because I finished
my piece last night.
You finished? Really? Mhm. That's wonderful.
Then just in time.
The exhibition is two days away.
To be
honest, I was worried about you.
Did I hear correctly that you've
finished your contest entry?
Yes. Then the regulations
require me to perform
an inspection, may I?
Be my guest. Do you mind
if I come along, too?
I'm eager to see Anne's work.
I suppose that's all right.
Meath ro. Lid. Pod!
What are you doing? Oh, nothing.
Where shall, um.
I got him out of the way.
Wait. No, I mean,
he's out for a walk. Yes.
You can't fool me.
You're snacking. What?
No, I'm just testing it.
The sugar
you make is so
beautiful and silky.
And in fact,
there's nothing like it.
I've never known such a flavor.
And that's somehow
different than snacking. Wait.
So when you're tasting it, you can
tell the difference in flavor.
All fairies can do that.
Are you impressed?
We didn't come here to listen
to you argue with a fairy.
All right, I apologize.
The climbing rose is a symbol
of the royal family,
and you've entwined it
with a fairy's wing.
Do you like it, sir? Uh, well.
I'd say this will do nicely.
I appreciate that.
Oh.
It's great. Your
piece is lovely.
Really? Thank you.
I'm confident in my own skills,
but now
that I've seen what you can do,
an I'm a bit uneasy.
Still, I'm honored that I get
to face you in the exhibition.
When we stand before the king,
we'll
find out who's a better sugar
artisan. Fair and square. Right?
Hmm. Your grinning ear to ear.
What's made you so happy?
Keith complimented my sugar
confection today, getting
praise from someone so talented.
Of course I'm happy. Huh?
Huh?
You again.
Do you need something?
I wouldn't be here if I didn't.
Listen, I ran into Sammy.
He said
that my uncle wanted to speak
with you in the workrooms.
He's looking for me. That's odd.
I'll be right back.
Uncle. I brought
an hallford to see you.
Mhm.
Thanks for that, Jonas. But Mr.
Radcliffe isn't here
at the moment.
Hey, Sammy. What is this?
So, Jonas, I bet you're furious.
Two days from now at the sugar
confectionery exhibition.
She's going to win by cheating.
It's just like last year.
Except for now.
You're going to humiliate
Keith instead, right?
What are you saying? I would
never do anything to Keith.
As soon as he saw your entry,
he said it made him uneasy.
It was the roses.
The skilled hands.
If you didn't have them,
let me go!
You're taking it too far.
Trust me.
I hate ants just as much
as you do. But that doesn't.
Mean that you can't.
You're with Radcliffe School.
Then you'll stand there
and watch till the end.
Ah! Red master!
Get back here! Jonas! Ha ha ha!
Hey, I have a question.
And this time,
it's a serious one.
What? Let's say a girl says she
loves you and she asks you for
a kiss.
How would you answer her?
From this point on, I will ignore
all of your serious questions.
Hans in trouble.
You have to help, man. Please.
So.
You damned humans!
Please don't kill themselves.
I will spare your lives.
But one day
I'll kill every one
of you without fail. I swear.
Oh. So.
I failed you.
It's my fault.
I let us be separated.
Thank you. I was so scared.
It was helpful.
Here. It's all right.
I heard about the incident
as master
of the Radcliffe Workshop
School, I must apologize.
There's no excuse. What an unfortunate
thing to happen here.
It's brought shame
upon our entire school.
My nephews failed me
for the last time. Huh?
That does it, Jonas,
is to be expelled.
Wait a minute, Mr. Radcliff.
Jonas wasn't.
Responsible.
No. If that's the case, then
who was it that attacked you?
Sammy did. Jonas was the one
who went to find some help.
But it was Sammy and his
friends who informed me of it.
That's the reason I came here.
Is that true?
Why would someone report
a crime they
had committed themselves?
I know what happened to you was
unpleasant,
but something shouldn't be said.
What? Sammy's worked
here since he was 12.
He's practically been
an artisan since birth.
He's one of my best charges.
I know that he would
never lie to me.
Sorry, but he did. In fact,
right before it happened,
Jonas came by here on an errand.
He said that Sammy
told him you wanted
an to go to the work area.
Does that sound familiar?
Silence that fairy now. After that,
he came back looking terrified.
Shut your mouth. Refused.
That's it. Please stop it.
Oh, shall.
You're the fairy who served
as model for Keith's entry.
The one who came
to Halford's rescue.
Tell me then,
who's to blame for this?
Most rotten apples tend to fall
from a rotten tree. Huh? Huh?
Huh? Then get out. You, Jonas.
Your fairies, the lot of you.
You're free to take
the peace that you made
in the three barrels
of sugar that you were fined.
Think of it as the workshop's compensation
for the inconvenience you suffered.
But, sir, that's not fair.
I said leave.